Matthew J. Estes

Phoenix, AZ 85013 | (480) 234-6894

Summary

Full stack web developer in training with extensive experience in education, training, and development. Recently completed a certificate in full stack development (JavaScript MERN Stack) from the University of Arizona, with a focus on intensive collaboration with colleagues and faculty on group projects. 10+ years experience as an adult educator, with recent expertise in translating in-person instruction to virtual and on-demand audiences. Certified supervisor and manager, with education and experience in job coaching, project management, and traditional HR topics. Formal education includes a law degree, with significant work experience related to legal writing and research.

Skills

Web Development

Front-End: HTML, CSS (Bootstrap, Materialize) JavaScript, jQuery, React.js, Handlebars.js Back-End: Node.js, Express.js, mySQL, Sequelize, NoSQL (MongoDB, Mongoose), APIs Project Management: Git, GitHub, Heroku

Instructional Design Software

Articulate Storyline, Adobe Captivate, Microsoft Office Suite, Adobe Acrobat, Adobe Photoshop

Accreditation

Certified Court Manager (Institute for Court Management), 2019 Arizona Court Supervisor (Arizona Supreme Court), 2017

Projects

- **"Bootcamp Adventure":** Deployed 8/2022 at hidden-falls-09723.herokuapp.com/, project available for review at hidden-falls-09723.herokuapp.com/, project available for review at hidden-falls-09723.herokuapp.com/, project available for review at hidden-falls-09723.herokuapp.com/, project available for review at hit will be a supplied to the falls-09723.herokuapp.com/.
 - An RPG-style game detailing a possible scenario for a student's programming bootcamp experiences, using the full MERN stack.
- **"90s Rewind"** | Deployed 6/2022 at https://group-project-90s-rewind.herokuapp.com/, project available for review at https://github.com/shanehancock64/GroupProject2
 - An e-commerce site making use of Node.js, Express.js, RESTful APIs, MySQL, Sequelize, Handlebars.js, MySQL, and Heroku.
- "Wildfire AQI Tracker": Deployed 4/2022 at github.com/matthewestes33/wildfireAQItracker, project available for review at https://matthewestes33.github.io/wildfireAQItracker/
 - A tracker to provide users with the up-to-date air quality index (AQI) for areas recently affected by wildfires, using JavaScript, APIs, and Materialize.

Employment

Arizona Supreme Court: Phoenix, AZ

3/2020 - 5/2022

Special Projects Administrator

Directed the Arizona courts' Leadership Institute's educational programming, and delivered curriculum and instruction to Arizona judicial officers, administrators, and staff.

- State Administrator of Institute for Court Management certification programs for over 600 Arizona court supervisors, managers, and executives.
- Staff for the Court Leadership Institute of Arizona, the Judicial College of Arizona, and the Judicial Staff Education Committee.
- Managing editor for 12 volumes of Judicial College of Arizona bench books and reference manuals.
- Author of nine modules of Limited Jurisdiction New Judge Orientation online education series.

Arizona Supreme Court: Phoenix, AZ

5/2018 - 3/2020

Special Projects Coordinator

Designed and executed new training solutions for Arizona's judicial officers, and led statewide initiatives to improve educational opportunities for the Arizona judiciary.

- Project Manager, annual Governor's Office of Highway Safety Judicial Conference
- Author, "Discrimination and Harassment" training for Arizona judiciary
- Author, Civil Traffic Hearing Officer Introduction online education series

Arizona Superior Court in Pima County: Tucson, AZ

9/2014 - 4/2018

Training & Education Coordinator

Designed, organized, delivered, and evaluated educational programming for Pima County judicial employees, in compliance with the requirements of the Arizona Code of Judicial Administration. Specialized in coordination and instruction of annual required diversity training for 1,000+ employees, including the introduction of implicit bias and cognitive bias training.

mindfish: Boulder, CO

9/2012 - 1/2015

Instructor, Curriculum Developer

Edited SAT and ACT exam curriculum for immediate national distribution. Taught hybrid courses in SAT, ACT, PSAT, SAT Subject Tests, and high school math in individual and small group settings. Average score improvement for students from pre-test to official test was over 200 points for SAT and over 3 points for ACT.*

Education

Full-Stack Coding Certificate, University of Arizona, 2022

Certificate in Web Development (JavaScript MERN Stack)

Sandra Day O'Connor College of Law, Arizona State University, 2009 Juris Doctorate

Barrett, The Honors College, Arizona State University, 2006

B.A., Philosophy, B.A., Religious Studies, summa cum laude

*Complete work and publications history available upon request.